Guide to the Reva Korda Papers, 1952-1991 and undated RL.11051
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Reva Korda Papers
1952-1991 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Korda, Reva, 1927-2008
RL.11051
4.0 Linear Feet
Copywriter and advertising executive with Gimbels and Macy's department stores and the Ogilvy & Mather agency.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Chronological Files; General Files; and Writings. Original order and folder titles were retained where feasible.
Biographical / Historical
Born Reva Fine, in New York, N.Y. 1927. AB English and Philosophy, Hunter College. Copywriter at Gimbels department store 1949-1951; Macy's 1951-1953. Junior copywriter at Ogilvy & Mather 1953. Career at Ogilvy & Mather: Senior Vice President 1962; Associate Copy Chief 1963; first female elected to Board of Directors 1975; U.S. Creative Head 1980; retired 1983. Published novel "Having It All" in 1991. Died 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Scope and Contents
Collection spans 1952-1991 and includes correspondence, storyboards and commercial scripts, reports, print advertisements and drafts of Korda's writings including her novel Having It All and television pilot proposal scripts. Companies represented include Gillette Gimbel's and Macy's department stores, Ogilvy & Mather, Hathaway shirts, Pepperidge Farm and Schweppes. Cosmetics advertising includes Gillette (Eve of Roma), Helena Rubenstein and Unilever (Dove soap). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Anthony Weir Papers; David B. McCall Papers; J. Walter Thompson Company. Nan Findlow Papers; Jock Elliott Papers; Joel Raphaelson Papers; Kenneth Roman Papers; Margaret Fishback Papers; Robert S. Smith Papers; William E. Phillips Papers
Advertising agencies -- New York; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising executives -- United States; Television scripts; Advertising -- Cosmetics; Korda, Reva, 1927-2008
- Chronological Files, 1954-1980s and undated
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, commercial scripts and other printed materials
  - 1954-1977, 11 folders (Box 1)
  - 1977-1979, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - 1980-1988 and undated, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - 1978 binder 1 (Box 3)
  - 1978 binder 1, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - 1978 binder 2, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - 1978 binder 3, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - 1978 binder 3 (Box 5)
  - 1979 binder 1, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - 1979 binder 3, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 1979 binder 3 (Box 6)
- General Files, 1952-1978 and undated
  Includes correspondence, commercial scripts and other advertising copy, print advertisements, and reports.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
  - Photographs, 1978 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 9)
  - Portfolio book, 1952-1955 and undated (Box 8)
  - Print advertisements--Conmar zippers, Dove, Helene Rubenstein, Korda Syndicate, Pepperidge Farm. Ron Carioca rum, Viyella flannel, 1953-1961 and undated (Box 9)
  - Print advertisements--Eve of Roma, undated (Box 9)
  - Print advertisements--Hathaway, 1958 and undated (Box 9)
  - Print advertisements--Schweppes, 1954 and undated (Box 9)
  - Print advertisements--Newsprint [Very Fragile]--Dove, Macy's, 1952-1956 and undated (Box 9)
  - Rolodex and contact file tray, undated (Box 10)
- Writings, 1953-1991 and undated
  Includes short stories, proposals for television pilots and sample scripts, and drafts and published versions of Korda's novel Having it all, along with an unpublished book-length manuscript.
  - Articles, 1967-1982 (Box 6)
  - Creative writing miscellaneous, 1953-1960s and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Do You Really Like the People You're Selling to? undated (Box 6)
  - Having It All, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Having It All press package, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Having It All uncorrected proof, 1991 (Box 6)
  - How the Ritual Ends; The Color of Catherine's Hair, 1955-1977` (Box 7)
  - Television pilot, miscellaneous ideas, undated (Box 7)
  - Television pilot, Noah's Ark, 1975-1979 (Box 7)
  - Television pilot, Who's Minding the Store?, 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - The Almost Perfect Neighbors, undated, 4 folders (Box 7)